本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
Our opponents chose to receive.
相手がレシブ選択しました
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
We'll be serving first.
先サブです
All right.
It's finally time for the qualifiers.
いよいよ代表決定戦
Everyone looks more nervous than usual.
やはりみんないつもより緊張しているように見えます
The third-years look especially nervous.
特に３年生は
Those are so awesome!
それいいなぁ
Your new glasses look so cool, Tsukishima!
かけぇなぁ
月島の新しいメガネ
You've been saying that almost every day lately, Hinata.
日向ここ最近毎日言てるな
You saying they're cool messes with my self-confidence, so please stop.
日向基準の「かこいい」は不安になるからやめてほしい
What'd you say?!
あんだと
じゃんこれやる
Ta-da! Here you go.
スポツグラスだよ
They're sports glasses.
I made sure to find some cool-looking ones.
見た目もカコイイの探したんだからな
If you wear those,
even blocking with your face won't be scary!
それ掛けてりゃ顔面ブロクだて怖くない
No, it'll still be scary.
いや怖いから
I don't care if it's Ushiwaka or Benkei. Go stop 'em all.
ウシワカだろうがベンケイだろうが止めて来いよ
１年の方が頼もしい顔してるてどういうことだよ
What's up with the first-years looking more reliable than us?
Us third-years don't have time to be intimidated!
３年がビビてらんねぇべ
All right!
試合は超楽しい遊びだろ
Matches are super fun, aren't they?
Fly
Simple and Strong
Let's have a good match!
お願いします
Episode Fifteen:
Playground
Simple and Strong
条善寺条善寺
Jouzenji! Jouzenji! Jouzenji!
We're finally at the qualifiers.
こから代表決定戦だ
そして相手はインハイ予選ベスト４
Our first opponent was a semifinalist at the interhigh prelims.
We've got our work cut out for us.
相手にとて不足はねぇ
一発目思いきり行けよ東峰
You'd better go all out on that first serve, Azumane!
烏野ファイ
Karasuno, fight!
Yeah!
旭さんナイサ
Give us a good serve, Asahi!
Get a nice, solid receive!
レシブ一本しかり
Man, that's intense!
キョウレツ
ナイスカバ
Nice save!
照島ラスト
You got the last hit, Terushima!
We can score here!
チャンスボル
Yahoo!
Nice hit!
ナイスファイト
エンドラインから強打かよ
A strong hit from the baseline?
On top of that, it was right after a quick spin.
しかも振り向きざまに
Normally, you'd return it with an underhand hit.
普通はアンダで返すとこですよね
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
ナイサ
Give us a good one!
オライ
I got it!
Left!
レフト
Simple and Strong
わしょいわしょい
Heave ho!
なんかこう
You know, it's like we're up against a really athletic baseball team during gym class.
体育ですげぇ運動能力高い野球部とかと試合してるみたいだ
確かに型に嵌てなくて
Yeah. Their plays aren't exactly cookie-cutter,
so we can't seem to read what they're gonna do.
何してくるかわかんない感じがそうですね
で問題はあれをマグレでやてんじゃないてとこだな
And the problem is none of that is happening by accident.
不確定要素は条善寺にとての普通で
Unpredictability is the name of the game for Jouzenji.
それこそが武器
Give us another good one!
もう一本
Come on, now!
すまんて
Sorry!
Shake it off!
ドンマイドンマイ
ボル拾て返して
Pick up the ball and give it to the other team!
もうすぐ調子に乗るんだから
Jeez... They get out of hand so quickly.
You're the only third-year left.
残てる３年お前だけだからな
あの調子者達が相手じゃ苦労が絶えないな
You must have your hands full trying to deal with them.
月島ナイサ
Give us a good one, Tsukishima!
A fast attack!
速攻
当然だけど普通の攻撃もできんだな
This shouldn't be a surprise,
but I guess they can attack normally too.
Karasuno
It went over the net! So lucky!
ラキネトイン
コンニャロ
Damn it!
Wow, nice reflexes!
ナイス反応
But can they continue the rally?
でも繋がらないか
Nice save, Hinata!
ナイス日向
Whoa, he's flying!
跳んだ
Look out!
危ない
I-It's Spider-Man!
ススパイダマンだ
In the back!
後ろ
Whoa, they got it back over the net!
返した
運動能力が高くて何やらかしてくるかわかんない奴
We also have some guys on our team
who are highly athletic and unpredictable.
そういうのうちにもいたな
ソォイ
Yeah!
Well, that was definitely surprising,
まぁ確かに今のもビクリだけど
but Karasuno hasn't even done their ridiculous attack yet.
でも烏野のとんでも技はまだ出てねぇじゃんな
C'mon! Bring out the killer serve!
行け殺人サブ
レシブがどういう形だろうと
The receive doesn't have to be flashy. As long as they get the ball in the air, they can do whatever is necessary.
上がりさえすればどうとでもできる
全員そう思ているし実際そうできる
That's what they all think,
and that's what they're able to do.
Damn it!
One more time! Just spike it, Jiri!
もう一発ジリダイレクト
よしゃ
All right!
Karasuno's been on the back foot the entire match.
烏野防戦一方じゃん
大地さんナイスレシブ
Nice receive, Daichi!
There's number ten's super fast attack!
来た
１０番の超速攻
Hey, Kageyama!
ヘイ影山俺達も負けてらんねぇぞ
We can't just sit here losing!
今のが噂の速攻か
So that was the fast attack I heard about.
Ow!
Awesome!
かけぇ
向こうの動きは読みづらいけどボルが消えるわけじゃなし
It's hard to predict our opponent's movements, but it's not like the ball's gonna disappear.
Let's calm down and have at 'em.
落ち着いて行くべ
Yeah!
ウェイ
Well done.
さすが
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
Number ten!
１０番１０番
All right!
しゃぁ
色々大ざぱなんだよな条善寺て
Jouzenji's really rough around the edges.
ブロクとかすぐポンポン跳んじゃて
Their blockers just keep jumping around, and they fall for feints a lot.
よく囮にひかかるし
なのになんだろうなあのしつこさというかやりづらさは
Yet they're so persistent and hard to play against.
I have a friend on the Jouzenji basketball team.
僕条善寺のバスケ部に友達いるんですけど
マジで
Really?
バレ部はいつも練習の半分以上
Apparently their volleyball team does nothing but two-on-two matches for over half of their practice time.
２対２のゲムをひたすらやているそうです
Nothing but two-on-two matches?
ひたすら２対２
That's rough!
Since they're used to playing in teams of two,
they don't expect anyone to get the ball for them,
それに慣れてるから誰かがやてくれるて感覚が薄くて
and all of them are constantly
setting up some sort of attack.
常に全員が攻撃を仕掛けるつもりでいると
Cover for me!
Leave it to me!
任せろ
バカたれちょとは譲れ
Idiots! Watch where you're going!
ドンマイドンマイ
だからこういうこともあるのかな
Which is probably why that sort of thing happens.
どいつもこいつもめんどくせぇ
They're all really annoying.
お前らも他校からはめんどくせぇて思われてるよ
People from other schools think you guys are annoying too.
Huh?!
田中さん
Tanaka!
Whoa!
ジリナイス
Nice one, Jiri!
今条善寺の前の攻撃はセタを除いて２枚
Right now, Jouzenji has two attackers in the front row, not counting their setter.
The other possibility is a back row attack.
あとはバクアタクか
俺にも打たせろ
Let me spike too!
Isn't he the setter? Who's going to set, then?
こいつセタだろ誰がトスを
後衛の奴が上げるのか
Someone from the back row is going to set?
What?!
Simple and Strong
わしょいわしょい
Heave ho!
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
Despite the circumstances,
I must say how they play is quite fun to watch.
いやはやそれにしても彼らのバレボルは見ていてとても楽しい
それは異論ない
I can't argue with that.
However, we can keep up with them in
terms of attacking with reckless abandon.
でも自由奔放な攻撃ならうちのも負けてませんよ
楽しく遊ぼうぜ
Let's have some fun and play.
全力で本気で遊ぶ
They go all out and play around.
In a match...
勝負事で
Huh?
本当に楽しむためには強さが要る
"To truly have fun, you need strength."
鳥養元監督が昔よく言てたんだて
Apparently, the former Coach Ukai said that a lot.
I didn't quite understand what
the meaning of "have fun" was.
楽しむてどういうことかよくわかんなかたんだけど
All right!
しゃぁ
But watching Jouzenji,
I'm wondering if this is what he meant.
条善寺を見てるとこういう感じかなて思うよ
楽しむ強さ
The strength... to have fun.
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
It might be because they're up against Karasuno, but they're playing around even more than usual.
烏野と影響し合てかいつにもマシて遊んでるな
Yes. When they're in the groove, they do play well.
ええやぱり乗るといいバレしますよね
Sorry! Sorry!
And that happens as soon as I compliment them.
褒めるとすぐこれだ
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
That little guy sure can jump!
ほんとちせぇのによく跳ぶな
ナイスワンチ
Good job getting a hand on it!
チャンスボル
Let's score off this!
Not to mention...
それに
しゃぁ
All right!
He's got such a stern face,
頭固そうな顔してるくせに
but that setter sure comes up with some crazy attacks!
ホント滅茶苦茶な攻撃してきやがるセタだなぁオイ
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
旭
Asahi!
Nice, Tsucchi!
ナイスつち
誰が打てくる
Who's gonna spike it?
ツアタクさせるか
A setter dump?!
I have to stop it!
Fly
All right!
Nice block, Kageyama!
影山くんナイスブロク
よしゃ
That... wasn't a block...
い今のブロク
顔面だたぞ
That was his face.
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
Time!
タイム
Kageyama, don't die!
影山死ぬな
He's not dying.
殺すなよ
血血が
Hey, we're switching you out
until your nose stops bleeding.
おい血ィ止まるまで交替だ
My nose isn't bleeding!
鼻血なんて出てません
Yes, it is. Why would even you lie about that?
出てるよなんでうそつくの
目は
Are your eyes okay?
They're fine.
大丈夫す
相手のテンションにつられて前のめりになちゃいましたかね
Did he get caught up in the excitement of the other team?
Well, this is a good opportunity to cool your head off.
まぁ頭冷やすにはいい機会だろ
You can't go back out until your nose stops bleeding,
so go get yourself looked over.
どうせ血止まるまで出られねぇし見てもらて来い
Just in case!
念のためですよ
Come on. Let's go.
行くぞほら
Hey, Kageyama!
ヘイ影山
I'll handle things while you're gone.
留守は任せろ
Yep. Leave it all to your upperclassmen.
そうそう先輩に任せなさいての
月島ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Tsukishima!
Huh? Karasuno is...
あれ烏野
わしょいわしょい
なんで１０番下げるんだろ
Why are they subbing number ten out?
He seems to be doing fine.
調子悪くなさそうなのに
I think they're going to use this opportunity to try other things.
この機会に他のことも試すんじゃないの
Besides,
それに
the other guys seem to be better at the fundamentals.
基礎プレは他の奴の方がうまいぽいし
What? Isn't that the truth?
なんだよほんとのことだろ
Aone developed a strange friendship with
Karasuno's number ten during the interhigh prelims.
青根はインタハイ予選の時に
烏野の１０番と妙な友情ができてたからなぁ
It may be like that for now.
今はまだそうかもしれない
Huh? Aone spoke!
青根が
しゃべた
And their number ten is aware of it.
それはあの１０番もわかてる
Hinata.
日向
For the past few months, Narita's spent quite a lot of time practicing with Sugawara as his setter.
ここ数ヶ月成田は菅原セタでのコンビを合わせてる時間が長い
Well, just watch your upperclassmen play from outside the court for a bit.
まぁ外から先輩達のプレを見てみろよ
Yessir.
Let's stop them here!
一本で切るぞ
成田しかり
You got this, Narita!
ちょとは落ち着きなよ
Calm down a little.
We know you want to be in there.
出たいのはわかるけど
I wanna play, and I wanna practice.
試合も出たいし練習もしたい
やることがいぱいだ
I have a lot to do.
Nice spike!
All right!
ナイスキ
ナイサ
ナイスナイス
That's it! Just like that!
Nice job!
その調子その調子
Right.
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
Give us a good one, Terushima!
照島ナイサ
All right!
Whoo! A service ace! Whoo!
サビスエス
あの一回で３点取たみたいなテンション腹立つ
That guy acts like he just scored three points!
It seriously pisses me off!
You're one to talk.
田中は人のこと言えないと思う
What?!
何だと
Don't let their excitement overwhelm you.
向こうのテンションに呑まれんなよ
We're gonna take the first set!
１セト目一気に取る
Shake it off!
ドンマイドンマイ
一本きてこう
Get one through!
Oh, Kageyama's back.
影山戻てきたな
Kageyama was all right.
影山くんは大丈夫でした
Yeah, looks that way. Thanks for checking up on him.
おみたいだなお疲れ
You okay?
But I guess they're not going to swap him back in yet.
大丈夫か
でもまだメンバは変えずに行くぽいな
Yes.
Nishinoya!
西谷
Got it!
オライ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
I guess you lost a handle on things.
留守は任せろて言てなかたか
Shut up!
うせぇな
I'll be able to get a handle on things soon!
近々そうできるようになる
That's the plan!
予定です
Nice spike.
ナイスキ
Nice spike!
Nice!
ナイス
We're not gonna lose.
負けねぇ
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
We have a chance here!
チャンスボル
Got it!
オライ
Synchronized attack: Sugawara version!
シンクロ攻撃菅原版
All right!
よしゃあ
With that...
これでセトポイント
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
we're on set point.
That thing where everyone starts
moving all at once looks awesome!
あの一斉に皆動き出すやつかけぇよな
Hey, so, like...
なあのさ
Don't tell me they're thinking about...
まさかあの子たち
成田一本ナイサ
Give us another good serve, Narita!
条善寺もシンクロ攻撃
Jouzenji's also doing a synchronized attack?!
All right!
よしゃあ
Karasuno                        Jouzenji
We used to do that a lot.
俺らもよくやてましたねあれ
Not bad, Narita.
やるじゃん成田
We still do sometimes.
今もたまにやるけどな
条善寺の今のシンクロ攻撃
Jouzenji's synchronized attack just now was
probably them copying what they saw on the fly.
たぶん見様見真似ぶつけでやたな
Huh? When they were losing?
え劣勢のしかもセトポイントでですか
Not to mention, we were on set point.
A part of it may be because it was only the first set.
I totally thought we could do it!
やれると思たのに
まだ１セト目だからてのもあるだろうが
It's scary how reckless they are.
おかねぇ無鉄砲さだな
気になていたんですが
This has been bothering me.
Jouzenji's banner doesn't really seem to mesh with how the team acts, right?
条善寺高校の横断幕
Simple and Strong
なんというかチムの感じと合てないですよね
If anything, something like
"Free and Wild" may be a better match.
どちらかというと自由奔放とかがしくりきます
Actually, a long time ago, or rather, up until recently,
いや昔つかごく最近まで
simplicity and strength described Jouzenji's team accurately.
まさに質実剛健なチムだたはずだ条善寺は
You guys should really think about the right time to try these things.
お前ら本当やるタイミング考えろよ
I totally thought we could pull it off.
行けると思たんすけどね
They took a set off you guys!
１セト取られたじゃねぇか
Just like all of you, they're a troublesome team if you let them get in the groove!
お前らと同じで乗せると結構厄介なチムだぞ
That number ten sure can jump.
あの１０番確かによく跳ぶよね
I mean, their motto is...
さすが飛べ
Fly
"Fly"!
And in comparison...
それに比べてうちの横断幕だせぇよ
Simple and Strong
our banner is so lame.
Let's get a new one ASAP.
早く新しいのにしようぜ
"Simple and Strong" is cool too!
かこいいじゃないの質実剛健だて
Well, there's no accounting for taste,
それは好みの問題だけどチムには合てないすよ
but it doesn't really fit the team.
At least not the current team.
少なくとも俺らの代つうかこれからの代には合てない
Actually, it won't fit future teams either.
I know, right?
だよな
Miyagi Prefectural
Jouzenji High School
I'm Anabara, and I will be your coach this year.
今年から監督を務める穴原だ
I'm going to rebuild this team from the ground up.
このチムを土台から作り変える
First, you'll get better at playing two-on-two.
まずは２対２で試合を成立させろ
I heard they have five second-years.
あそこ２年が５人も入てんだてよ
Seriously?
Yahoo!
マジか
And they made it to the semifinals? That's awesome.
それでベスト４とかすげぇな
Terushima!
照島
Huh?
Eventually, there'll come a time that isn't fun.
必ず楽しくない時間はやてくる
What'll you do then?
その時お前はどうする
Even then,
それでも楽しんでみせますよ
I'll do my best to have fun!
We're gonna fool around even more!
もともと遊ぶべ
Yeah!
Jouzenji                         Karasuno
Man...
That weird duo's coming back?
やぱ復活してくんのかよあの変なコンビ
Hinata, Kageyama, stay calm!
日向影山落ち着けよ
Will you two shut the hell up?
うるせぇよ
Looks like you're back, Mini Spider-Man!
戻てきたなミニスパイダマン
It's boring without your attacks!
やぱお前の攻撃がないと地味だからな
Boring?
地味
Like your captain, for instance.
お宅のキャプテンとかさうまくてもなんか地味
He's really good, but he's boring.
Right... Though I don't really understand what you mean.
よく分かんないすけど
Anyway, we're gonna have tons of fun and win this next set!
とにかく次はうちが遊び勝つ
I still can't beat you one-on-one, Mr. Close-Cropped Hair.
俺は１対１ではまだ刈り上げさんに勝てないけど
Hey, don't give me a weird nickname!
おい変なあだ名つけんなよ
Got it. I'll be more careful.
But with these guys on my side, there's no way I'll lose!
分かたオレも気をつけよう
このメンバだたら負けないです
Leave it to me!
頼む
任せろ
Give us a good serve, Higashi!
東ナイサ
Nishinoya!
西谷
Got it!
よしゃ
Ah!
言わんこちゃない
I warned you guys!
Wow! Those are some amazing reflexes!
すごい反応
Actually, I think he was expecting that.
ていうか今のは読んでたぽいな
Huh?
Nice job wiping their asses for them, Daichi!
大地さんナイス尻拭い
Don't phrase it that way!
その言い方止めろての
Here!
He's going for another insane hit!
またムチャな体勢から
All right!
よしゃあ
今度こそ決また
We got it this time!
S-Sorry about that!
すすいません
Thanks for covering for me!
Thanks!
ナイスカバ
あざす
No matter how often we tell you to calm down,
どんだけ落ち着けて言ても
I had a feeling you guys would still screw the first try up
一発目はお前ら絶対やらかすと思たんだよね
because you'd get too excited.
力みすぎて
俺にはド派手なプレは無理だけど
I'm no good at flashy moves,
土台なら作てやれる
but at the very least, I can create a foundation.
Anyway, go play your heart out.
まあ存分にやんなさいよ
あざす
Yessir!
In terms of being free and wild,
Jouzenji isn't better or worse than we are.
自由奔放さという点じゃ条善寺はうちに勝るとも劣らねえ
But...
that's not all we have.
うちはそれだけじゃねぇぞ
All right!
Jouzenji                     Karasuno
よしゃあ
Their lead is widening.
点差開いてきたな
Let's get hyped up!
気合い入れろ
Yeah!
Damn it!
上がたラスト
It's up! Finish it off!
Get back!
下がれ
Nice, Tanaka!
田中ナイス
All right!
よしゃあ
A counterattack!
カウンタ
Yeah!
しゃあ
Damn, their number ten is out of control!
クソあの１０番手に負えねぇつの
Nice spike, Hinata!
日向ナイスキ
あざす
Thanks!
I-I'm sorry!
すみません
Jouzenji                         Karasuno
ドンマイドンマイ
Don't worry about it!
We'll take this set in one swoop!
一気に取るぜ
アウト
Let it go!
ドンマイドンマイ
Shake it off!
Give us a good one, Daichi!
大地さんナイサ
Got it!
オライ
すまん
Sorry!
Bastards!
こんにゃろ
Is he going to do a setter dump?
ツで打つ気か
Yeah, you go!
いいぞいたれ
Crap...
All right!
よしゃ
The other team called for a timeout!
向こうタイムアウト取た
All right!
しゃあ
It's good to be on the offensive,
but Jouzenji is just rushing themselves.
攻めるのはいいけど焦てるな条善寺は
Let's get psyched up!
テンション上げてくぜ
You got it! Spirit! More spirit!
およ気合い気合い
It'll all work out!
何とかなるて
So what should we do with number ten's fast attack?
じゃあの１０番の速攻どうする
What should we do?
どうする
Wh-What'll we do?
どどうしよう
Don't think too hard!
あんま考え込むなて
We just have to rush in and attack! Rush in hard and fast!
もとこうがと攻めねぇとがと
What are you going to do now, Misaki?
三咲はこれからどうすんの
Miyagi Prefectural
Jouzenji High School
I still haven't found a successor,
私はまだ後釜も見つかてないし
so I think I'll stick around until spring nationals.
春高まで残ろうと思う
That's a relief.
それならちょと安心だわ
Those guys are really good when they're doing well,
あいつら調子がいい時はいいけど
but they're probably still frail when they lose their rhythm,
崩れたらたぶんまだ脆いから
ケツ叩いてやてよ
so you'll have to spank them for me.
I don't think they'll listen to me.
私の言うことなんか聞かないと思うけど
That's not true.
そんなことねぇよ
You're right! Let's rush in!
そうだよながと行こうぜがと
All right!
よしゃあ
Rush in!
What's this whole "rushing in" bit?!
がとて何よ
Huh?
You're trying too hard to make something happen with just spirit and excitement.
気合いとテンションで何とかしようとしすぎ
必ず楽しくない時間はやてくる
Eventually, there'll come a time that isn't fun.
その時お前はどうする
What'll you do then?
Even then,
それでも楽しんでみせますよ
I'll do my best to have fun!
You're going to have fun when you're losing or playing poorly?
劣勢でも不調でも楽しむ
Anyone who thinks that way is a creep or a weirdo!
そんなやつがいるとしたら変人か変態よ
M-Misaki? Is something wrong?
み三咲どうした
I'm sorry, Coach.
すみません先生
でも自分たちの弱さ
They'll never become painfully aware of their weaknesses unless I say this right now,
目の当たりにした時に言てやんないと痛感しないと思うので
so please let tell them.
今言わせてください
Huh? Uh, okay...
Okudake told me to give these guys a good spanking.
奥岳くんにこいつらのケツ叩いてくれて頼まれてるので
Spanking?
Hana...
華さんが
...just said "spanking"!
ケツて言た
Yeah, the situation right now isn't fun.
まあ確かに今の状況は楽しくないす
I hate to say it, but those guys are playing a lot more freely than we are.
悔しいけどあいつらのほうが自由に遊んでる
Okudake always used to say that to play,
you first need a playground.
遊ぶにはまず遊び場が必要だて奥岳くんがよく言てた
楽しくない時間を我慢して
Bear with the times that aren't fun,
and play the match out to the very end.
最後までちゃんと遊んでみなさいよ
I'm pretty sure I just heard the
pretty girl over there say "spank."
向こうの美女の口からケツと聞こえたような
What's wrong?
どうしたの
Kiyoko...
潔子さん
I'm not sure why I'm asking, but would you scold us too?
よく分かんないけど俺らのことも叱てもらえませんか
Also, please do it in the most condesc—
できれば見下すように
しません
No.
Then will you—
じゃあ
尻も叩きません
I won't spank you, either.
潔子さんのお口から「尻」いただきました
We got "spank" to flow from Kiyoko's luscious lips!
Jouzenji                        Karasuno
We're halfway through the second set.
２セト目半ばにして
こからが第２ラウンドて感じかな
This is where "round two" begins, huh?
条善寺のやつら変幻自在のバレだな
Jouzenji's style of volleyball is always changing.
俺たちだて負けてません
So is ours!
ロリングヘドバト
Rolling... Headbutt!
ノヤさんかけぇ
You're so cool, Noya!
That's... not volleyball.
それバレじゃないな
Episode Sixteen:
Next
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ次へ
"Next."